Guide to the Lillian Herlands Hornstein Papers 1930-1980 MC.140
New York University Archives
Lillian Herlands Hornstein Papers
1930-1980
New York University Archives
Hornstein, Lillian Herlands, 1909
MC.140
30 Linear Feet 30 linear feet (26 boxes)
The Hornstein collection documents the work of a prominent Chaucerian and English scholar whose entire career developed at New York University. The collection contains Hornstein's research material on Chaucer's literature, including correspondence, bibliographical indexes, manuscripts, papers and articles.
Arrangement
Ia. Research on Chaucer's Man of Law's Tale for the Chaucer Variorum Ib. Bibliographical Index Ic. Chaucer's Manuscripts II. NYU Class-Related Material III. Linguistics IV. Miscellaneous Research Material V. Personal Papers and Articles
Material is arranged either alphabetically or chronologically. Researchers should consult series descriptions for individual series arrangement.
The files are grouped into the following series:
Missing Title
Ia, Research on Chaucer's Man of Law's Tale for the Chaucer Variorum
Ib, Bibliographical Index
Ic, Chaucer's Manuscripts
II, NYU Class-Related Material
III, Linguistics
IV, Miscellaneous Research Material
V, Personal Papers and Articles
Scope and Content Note
The Hornstein collection documents the work of a prominent Chaucerian and English scholar whose entire career developed at New York University. The collection contains Hornstein's research material on Chaucer's literature, including correspondence, bibliographical indexes, manuscripts, papers and articles.
Another important part of the collection documents Hornstein's teaching. The areas relate to classes taught at NYU and Linguistics and contain syllabi, notes, PhD exam lists, and corrected student papers. The classes she taught are ordered by number, and they vary from old and medieval english literatures and languages, to history of the English Language, to contemporary english literature. There are also some syllabi from colleagues. Of note in this section is the portion extensively dedicated to her professor and mentor Margaret Schlauch, also an NYU English scholar and Chaucerian. The second section of the material pertains to the study of language and linguistics beyond the limits of her teaching needs.
A large section of the collection (about 10 boxes) relates both to her academic research and personal interests. For example there are files on Authographs, Iconography, the Female Serpent, Israel, Folklore and Folktales, Medieval drama and Music, 15c Arthurian Saga, Zodiac, Bocaccio, Freud, Jung, Jack Kerouac and Dieting. It would be useful to look into these files, to double check for extra or missing material in the other sections. It is in a rather chaotic order and everything seems to have been saved. Finally, the last box of the collection contains Hornstein's personal notebooks, speeches, papers and published articles.
The Hornstein papers offers rich and extensive materials for Chaucerians, english medievalists and linguists. This collection would also be very useful for anyone interested in the history of NYU English Department.
Historical/Biographical Note
Lillian Herlands Hornstein was born in Brooklyn, New York in 1909 and entered Washington Square College in 1925. She received her B.S. summa cum laude(1929), M.A. (1930) and her PhD. "with distinction" (1940) from New York University. Prof. Margaret Schlauch was her inspiration and favorite professor in the Medieval English Literature field. The topic of Prof. Hornstein's PhD thesis was a study of the sources of The King of Tars. She started as a graduate assistant in 1930 and became full professor in 1959. She retired as Professor Emerita of English in May, 1974. She received the "Great Teacher" award granted by the Alumni federation, in 1970, the W.S.C. Alumni Achievement award in 1973, and the NYU Presidential Citation, 1974. She was married to George D. Hornstein, Professor of Law at NYU.
Dr. Hornstein was a member of Phi Beta Kappa and of the consultative Board of the Modern Humanities Research Association, and was Chairman of Middle English at the Modern Language Association (1953-54, 1964-65, 1970). She was the President of the Academy of Literary Studies(1975-76), the Medieval Club of N.Y. (1963), the New York Council College Teachers of English (1950-51)and the Society for the Libraries of NYU She was also very involved in numerous NYU associations and committees.
Her publications show her wide interests in the field of literature. She compiled a Reader's Companion to World Literature(1956). She also participated in the Manual of Writings in Middle English (1968). She published her studies of the King of Tars in various literary journals. One of its versions, published in the PMLA, was voted one of the three best articles on literary criticism from the first 75 years of that journal. After she retired from NYU, she researched thoroughly Chaucer's Man of Law's Tale for the Chaucer Variorum.
Her contributions to society and academia are well accounted for in the Dictionary of American Scholars, Who's Who of American Women, Who's Who in World Jewry, Who's Who of Women in Education and the Dictionary of International Biography.
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted.
Please contact the University Archivists with specific questions regarding restrictions.
Provenance
This collection came to the University Archives from the estate of Lillian Herlands Hornstein.
Correspondence.; Art, Medieval |v Addresses, essays, lectures.; Literature |x History and criticism.; English literature |x Middle English, 1100-1500 |x History and criticism |v Addresses, essays, lectures.; Articles.; Postcards.; Notebooks; Speeches.; Essays.; Posters.; Kolve, V. A.; Petrarca, Francesco, 1304-1374; Gallo, Ernest; Elliott, Ralph Warren Victor; Joyce, James, 1882-1941; Benson, C. David; Braddy, Haldeen, 1908-1980; Chaucer, Geoffrey, -1400; New York University; David, Alfred, 1929-; Allen, Judson Boyce, 1932-1985
- Series I.a: Research on Chaucer's Man of Law's Tale for the Chaucer Variorum
  Scope and Contents note
  Several drafts, collations, drafts and bibliographies kept roughly in original order, bypage number. There is also correspondence with Ruggiers, Levy and Ross related to thisedition. (Boxes 1-6)
  - Index for MLT, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058120 2
  - 1-11, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 12-29, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 30-47, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 48-75, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 77-100, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 110-189, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 197-235, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 243-247, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 252-259, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 270-278, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 280-315, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 410-420, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 421-429, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 430-439, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 440-449, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 450-459, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 460-469, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 470-479, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 480-489, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 490-499, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 500-509, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 540-549, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 550-559, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 560-569, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 570-579, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 580-589, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 600-609, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 610-619, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 620-629, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 630-639, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Misc. up to 1117, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 1100-1162, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Chaucer Variorum edition correspondence, Levy, Ross, Ruggiers., undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Levy's questions 1-15, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Levy questions 16-30 (related to Canterbury Tales), undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Levy questions 31-50, Notes on pictures in appendix, additions and Princeton Notes. For book on Chaucer's No Man's Law., undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Thomas W. Ross Collations, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058121 0
  - Chaucer's Man of Law's tale. Incipit Prologue legis periti 1-100. Original Cx'-TR2 Printed texts collated. WR-PR. Superseded by long sheets., undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Incipit prologue 101-200, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Incipit prologue 201-300, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Incipit prologue 301-400, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Incipit prologue 401-500, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Incipit prologue 501-600, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Incipit prologue 601-700, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Incipit prologue 701-800, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Incipit prologue 801-900, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Incipit prologue 901-1000, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Incipit prologue 1001-1100, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Incipit prologue 1101-1162, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Hornstein's Introduction notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Prohemie lines 1-39, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Prohemie lines 40-89, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Prohemie lines 80-129, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Prohemie lines 130-189, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Prohemie lines 190-299, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Prohemie lines 300-369, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Prohemie lines 360-379 Episode related to the femenine serpent, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Prohemie lines 370-419, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Prohemie lines 420-480, undated- (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058122 8
  - Prohemie lines 481-520, undated- (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Prohemie lines 521-569, undated- (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Prohemie lines 570-629, undated- (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Prohemie lines 630-699, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Prohemie lines 700-799, undated- (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Prohemie lines 800-899, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Prohemie lines 900-999, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Prohemie lines 1000-1099, undated- (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Prohemie lines 1100-1190, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Commentary "Man of Law's tale" 1-99, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Commentary "Man of Law's tale" 100-289, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Commentary "Man of Law's tale" 300-549, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Commentary "Man of Law's tale" 550-899, undated- (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Commentary "Man of Law's tale", undated- (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Guildhall record of Chaucer, undated- (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1429 Case. Hearing on Jan. 1430, in form of dialogue, first in any place in the world., undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Bibliographies on Chaucer and Medieval English Literature. MLT Manuscript, undated- (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - The Miller's tale edited by Thomas W. Ross, undated- (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Henry Bradshaw's Idea of order of The Canterbury tales, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Alfred David's The Shorter Poems. Introduction and Critical Introduction, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Manciple's Prologue and Tale: Textual Introduction, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Chaucer related correspondence, undated- (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058123 6
  - Chaucer's Man's tale of Lawes. Corpus of textual variants, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - lines 1-100. Title and Prohemie. Corpus of variants, lines 101-200., undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Corpus of variants, 201-300, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Corpus of variants, 301-400, undated- (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Corpus of variants, 401-500, undated- (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Corpus of variants, 501-600, undated- (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Corpus of variants, 601-700, undated- (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Corpus of variants, 701-800, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Corpus of variants, 801-900, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Corpus of variants, 901-1000, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Corpus of variants, 1001-1100, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Corpus of variants, 1100-1190, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Notes for MLT edition I, undated- (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Notes for MLT edition II, undated- (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Notes for MLT edition III, undated- (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Notes for MLT edition IV, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Notes for MLT edition V, undated- (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Notes for MLT edition VI, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Notes for MLT edition VII, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Notes for MLT edition VIII, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Notes for MLT Manuscripts, undated- (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Notes for MLT Editions, undated- (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Chaucer's Man's tale of Law, lines 1-100, Furnival G-Text and prohemie. xerox collation all printed edition., undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058124 4
  - Man's tale of Law 101-200 CX'-PR, undated- (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Man's tale of Law 201-300 CX'-PR, undated- (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Man's tale of Law 301-400 CX'-PR, undated- (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Man's tale of Law 401-500 CX'-PR, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Man's tale of Law 501-600 CX'-PR, undated- (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Man's tale of Law 601-700 CX'-PR, undated- (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Man's tale of Law 701-800 CX'-PR, undated- (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Man's tale of Law 801-900 CX'-PR, undated- (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Man's tale of Law 901-1000 CX'-PR, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Man's tale of Law 1001-1100 CX'-PR, undated- (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Man's tale of Law 1101-1179 CX'-PR, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Ruggiers notes I, correspondence and bibliography for him, editor of the, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Ruggiers notes II., undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Bibliographies to be checked I. Related to Chaucer., undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Bibliographies to be checked II, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Man of Law's Headlink, undated- (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - General introduction, Prior to last draft, Hornstein's edition of Chaucer's Man of Law's tale., undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058125 1
  - Prior to last draft-First part. Roughly the first 100 pages of the Man of Law's Tale., undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Prior to last draft-Second part. Roughly from page 701-1190, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Prior to last draft-Third part., undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Prior to last draft-Fourth part incluidng: Manuscripts and Textual tradition, The time of the day in the Headlink, Ernest and Game: Homo ludens, Chaucer-Gower versions of MLT., undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Prior to last draft. Astrolabe, science Astrology, "Prose.", undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Last Draft I. Table of contents, Preface, Abbreviations, Manuscripts, editions. Pages 1-188. Last Draft II. Pages 189-332., undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - The Man of Law's prologue and Tale., undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Text typed and modernized. Single lines., undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Introduction: Characters, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - MLT-Appropriate-Sergeant. Rough Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - MLT-Genre. Draft and notes., undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Glosses-Furnivall, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Folktale of Accused Queen-not included., undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Six Text 1163-90, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Emare, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Corpus Christi, Esquire. Manuscript, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Ha4-Sompnour 1179-WBP and Harley 7334, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Wells, Severs and Hartung correspondence about Manual of the Writings in Middle English., undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - MLT-Manuscripts, misc., undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Hengwrt Manuscript, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Blake Text 1980 ed.Hg., undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Endlink, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Chaucer Manuscripts and Texts, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Trevet's tale of Constance, origins of the Man of Law's Tale., undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Man of Law's tale Bibliography, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - The New Chaucer society Membership List, 1986-87, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Chaucer, New books reviews, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Series I.b: Bibliographical Index
  The bibliographical material is organized alphabetically and includes correspondence,essays and publications by other scholars.(Boxes 7-8, See also index card collection inbox 10 and box 21/25-35)
  - Bibliographical Index A-D, undated (Box 7, Folder 1.a)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058126 9
  - Bibliographical Index E-H, undated (Box 7, Folder 1.b)
  - Bibliographical Index I-O, undated (Box 7, Folder 1.c)
  - Bibliographical Index P-Z, undated (Box 7, Folder 1.m)
  - Allen, Judson Boyce, undated (Box 7, Folder 1.e)
  - Backstrom, P.O., undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Baum, Paul F., undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Burrow, J., undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Baker, J.H., undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Bell Edition 1854-1855, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Benson, C. David, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Blake 1980 Edition, undated- (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Bloch, Marc, undated- (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Bloomfield, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Boethius, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Boitani-Torti, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Boyd, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Braddy, Haldeen, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Brewer, Derek, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Brown, Carleton, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Capozzi, Frank, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Chute, Marchette and Chambers Edition, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Crampton, G.R., Cooper, Helen, Coghill, N., undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Cox, Lee Sheridan, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Curry, Walter Clyde, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Dean, Ruth J., undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Von During, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - David, Alfred, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Dempster, Germaine, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Duffy, Bernard I. 1947, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Donaldson, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Eade. J.C., undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Eco, Umberto, undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Eisner, Sigmund, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Elliott, Ralph W.V., undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Everett, 1950, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Ferris, Sumner, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Fiedler, Edward 1844, undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Finnegan 1976, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Fisher, John H., undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Friend, Albert and Frye, N., undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Furnivall, 6-text, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Gallo, Ernest and Gopen, George, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Gardner, John 1977, undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Griffin 1956, Gillmeister, 1974, undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Gregg, Joan, undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Hawkins, Laurence Faulkner, undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Harty, Hamel, Hoffman, Hinton, undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Hertzberg G., undated (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Higonnet, Ethel Cardwell, undated (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Hume and Hyams, undated (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Huppe, Isaacs, undated (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Johnson, James. Chaucer allusions, undated (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Lounsbury, Thomas R. and Kean, P.M., undated (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Kane, Kaske, Kelly, Ker, Knight, Kerkhoff, Koch, undated (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Knowlton, undated (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Knight, Stephen, undated (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Kolve, V.A., undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058127 7
  - Krappe, A.H., undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Loomis, Dorothy Bethurum, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Labriola, Lambkin, Lancashire, Legge, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Lawrence, W.W., undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Lowes. J.L., undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Magoun Jr. Francis P., undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Mahoney, John, F., undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Masui, Michio, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - McNeal and Mehl, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Middleton and Miller, Robert P., undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Mismikin, Alice S., undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Ovid, Payne, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Pearsall, Pollock and Maitland, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Peed, Patterson, Prins, Paye, Pollard, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Palmer, Peck, Preston, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Ragusa, Isa, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Reinhard, Robertson, Reiss, Robbins, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Robinson, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Roddy, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Rose, Rosenfeld, Roxburgh, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Rubey, Ruggiers, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Schless, Spearing, Spiers, Skeat, Scheps, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Samuel, Shelly, Severs, Suggett, Theiner, Taylor, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Shapley, Stugrin, Skeat, Spurgeon, Shoaf, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Tedeschi, Tilley, Tupper, Tolkien, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Tyrwhitt, Utley, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Weissman, Hope Phyllis and Wenzel, Sigfried, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Whithread, Wynn, Williams and Wood, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous Bibliographical material A-H, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Bibliographical material J-W, undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous Chaucer Publications and articles, undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - MHRA Newsletter (Spring of 1983 and 1986), undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - The Chaucer Newsletter (1979-1987), undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Medieval Academy News (1980, 1984, 1987), undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Ford Madox Brown, undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Comitatus. Studies in Old and Middle English Literature No. I December 1970. English medieval Club. UCLA., undated (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - College English. April 1969, Oct. 1974, February 1975, undated (Box 8, Folder 39)
- Series I.c: Chaucer's Manuscripts
  They are not in alphabetical order. Most of them are dated. (Boxes 9-10/6, see also box15/14, 24/27 and box 25)
  - Pynson, R. (1492) (1526), undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058129 3
  - Furnivall, Frederick. Six-Text, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Caxton (1478), undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Wright (1847), undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Thynne (1545), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Worde, W.D. (1498), undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Urry, J. (1721), undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Tyrwhitt (1798), undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Speght (1598, 1602), undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Ad3, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Barlow (c.1450-80), undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Egerton, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Manly, John M. (1940), undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Legg, Wicham J. (1969), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Robinson, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Cambridge University Library, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Ellesmere, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Helmingham, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Hengwrt, undated (Box 9, Folder 18.b)
  - Manuscripts Texts of Editions of MSS, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Href11, D1, Fi, En2, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Correale, Robert M. Chaucer's Manuscript of Trevet's Les Cronicles, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Markwardt, Bruno. Worte und Werte, 1961, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Pratt, Robert. Published articles about Chaucer's Canterbury tales, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Index Librorum Prohibitorum, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Gutenberg's bible, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)